# **JOSEPH "MIKE" PRINCE**

# Software Developer

## **PERSONAL PROFILE**

After spending 10 years in Special Operations Aviation maintenance I was looking for a change in career. A logic and design college class introduced me to the Python language and after learning the basics I realized that I really enjoyed creating things on my computer. I was recently made the career change to software development by attending Nashville Software Schools full stack web development bootcamp.

#### **CONTACT DETAILS**

- Mobile: 931-494-0783
- michaelprince3@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/michaelprince3
- https://github.com/michaelprince3

## **PROJECTS**

### **Nutshell Group Project**

A JavaScript web application that allows a user to save news articles, Tasks and Events as well as chat with and save friends. For the project I was responsible for the events section of the site.

#### **Projectile Project Planner**

A project planning application to save future, active and completed projects. A single page web application built using React with hooks. Using json server for persistent data storage. Styled with Material UI and CSS.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Nashville Software School**

Full stack web Development Jan 2020 - June 2020

#### US Army

Various Military Schools attended 2007-2018

### DeVry University

Business Management 2016 - 2019

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Full Stack Software Developer**

Nashville Software School | Jan 2020 - Present Six-month full-stack Web Development boot camp. Using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python / Django

- · Utilized Git/GitHub for version control and issue tracking
- HTML/CSS used to create simple web pages
- JavaScript used to allow CRUD functionality in web applications
- React using hooks for functional component based web design
- dbdiagram.io used to create entity relationship diagrams
- JSON and API fetch used for data storage and retrieval

## **Special Operations Aviation**

US Army | 2007 - 2018

- Manage 14 employees meeting production requirements in repair and maintenance of aircraft assigned to Special Operations Assault Helicopter Company.
- Responsible for the training and certification of 14 employees on regularly updated inspection methods.
- Conduct quality control (QC) maintenance and repair inspections to aircraft systems, resulting in zero incidents over three-year period.
- Manage daily production requirements for powertrain shop while supervising and mentoring 14 employees.
  Received jobs from hangar Production Control Office and various flight companies for assignment to available personnel. Completed work orders, authorizations and job related documentation.
- Provide support for US Army programs that include Sexual Harassment/Assault Response and Prevention program, Equal Opportunity, and Equal Employment Opportunity.
- Personally responsible for inspection and repair of \$300 million worth of parent organizations equipment.